(logo whizzing)
(soothing music)
- [Meng] Hi, and welcome to session 18
of my swiftUI course.
So today we're gonna learn
how to animate this view
above the sidebar, and also the tab bar.
As a result is going to
be also above the navbar,
which means that we won't have
to create a custom title anymore.
And we will be able to
use this sidebar toggle,
which is on the navbar.
Now back to Xcode, we're
gonna go to navigation
and we're gonna go to content view.
So right now if you're on the iPhone,
it's gonna use the top bar
otherwise on the iPad, the sidebar.
What we're going to do
is to put both of them
to reference courses view.
As a result, courses view will be managing
the sidebar and a tab bar.
So let's go to courses view.
Now here we're going to
create a separate instance
of the sidebar and the top bar,
and it needs to reference the content part
of the courses view.
First of all, we're going
to click the top menu
to find the full content.
And here, let's double
click the curly braces
to find the end, and right after that,
let's type var tab bar camel case
of type some view, curly braces,
then we're gonna go to
the top bar dot Swift,
and we're going to copy
everything, including the tab view.
So copy, go back to courses view
and paste that inside the curly braces.
Now for the first item,
instead of courses view,
we're going to reference content, great.
Let's do the same for this sidebar.
So double click on the curly braces
and right after that type var sidebar
of type some view curly braces,
then we're gonna go to the sidebar,
and for the content, we're
going to copy the list,
including the list style modifier,
then go back to courses view,
paste that inside the sidebar.
So just like the structure in the sidebar,
where we have the navigation
view, as well as the content,
we're going to do the
same in courses view.
So come on and click on
List, embed in v stack,
change v stack two navigation view.
Then after the list style
modifier, we're gonna put content.
Now we're also missing two
modifiers for the title
as well as the toolbar.
So we're gonna go back to the sidebar,
and here in the body, right after content,
we're gonna copy, navigation
title and toolbar.
And then go back to courses view,
we're gonna put that after
list style, so that's it.
And the reason why the
sidebar is a little bit
more complicated is because
of the platform condition.
Now the sidebar and the
tab bar has to be here
because we are referencing the content.
Once we have this setup, we
can go back to the very top.
And this is where we're
managing every view.
So right now it's simply
calling the content directly
and we're hiding the navigation bar.
Instead of doing that,
we can reference the tab bar directly.
Now what is interesting
here is that the Z stack
is stacking the tab bar
underneath the full content,
which means that the full content
is going to animate above,
so, if we resume the preview,
you will see that when I tap on any cart,
the tab bar is underneath now.
And because of that, we can use the navbar
and we can also remove
the custom large title.
So in content, let's
remove the text element.
And right after scroll view,
we can put the navigation title.
So after z index dot navigation
title, set it to courses.
And because of that, when I scroll,
you can see this navbar and the animation
is going to be on top without a problem.
So what's left to do at this
point is to make it work
with a sidebar for the iPad.
In order to detect the
largest screen on the iPad,
we're gonna have to set the
environment, so at environment,
parentheses, backward slash
dot, horizontal size class,
var horizontal size class.
Let's set the platform
condition so that this code
only runs on iOS, type pound, if OS, iOS
then after that, and if.
Next let's go to body
where we reference tab bar,
we're gonna set if horizontal size class,
equal equal compact, curly braces,
then we can put the tab bar.
Else, we can reference
the sidebar, awesome.
So now we can test this
on the iPad 11 inch.
And voila, we have exactly
the same UI as before,
except now we're using
the navbar, but also,
the animated fullscreen
is above the sidebar,
and the tab bar as well.
Another big advantage is that
now that we're using the nav bar,
the sidebar toggle is now always present.
One last thing we need to
do is to test for the Mac.
So let's select the Mac and
try to build it Command + B.
Now it's giving us an error.
So let's look at it and here it says that
the navigation bar trailing
option for the toolbar
is not available for the Mac.
So even though we're not using the sidebar
from the courses view for the Mac,
it is still running the code.
And that's because in
content view for the Mac,
it's going to sidebar first,
and then from sidebar,
it's running courses view,
which happens to have this code.
So in this case, we can just
set a platform condition,
pound if OS, iOS and then at the end
of navigation view, and if.
Let's not forget to add
view builder for sidebar.
Great, now we can run the code.
And the Mac App is working
perfectly just like before,
but this time without
the custom large title.
In the next session, I wanna show you
how to add reusable components
and modifiers to the library
so that you can easily
insert them from the menu.
So I'll see you in the next session.
(logo swooshing)