(upbeat music)
- [Meng] Hi and welcome
back to session nine
of my Swift UI course.
Today, we're gonna look
into delayed transition
and asymmetric transition
so that we can open this card,
and before even showing the content,
which is kind of
overlapping with the card,
it's going to wait.
So it's gonna show the card first,
and then the content later.
If you scroll down a little bit
and look at the transition
and replace .opacity with dot,
you're gonna find more
options such as asymmetric,
and then you can see that
the type is AnyTransition.
Now, what is interesting here
is that you can set the animation timing
for your transition.
So to do that, we're going to remove dot
and put AnyTransition.opacity
.animation.
And this is where we can
set the animation timing.
In this case, we're gonna use .spring(),
and because we're using .animation,
we can also set multiple
animation options.
So if you set the value type
Animation with capital A,
you're gonna be able
to set after .spring().delay
and set it to 0.3, for example.
Let me indent the code a little bit.
So we have the transition
and then for this transition,
we have multiple options such
as what kind of transition?
In this case, it's opacity.
And for that transition, we
have the animation timing.
Then for the animation timing,
we have the spring behavior,
but also we added a delay of 0.3 seconds.
And I can just put this on the next line.
So this is my entire transition
with all of these options.
To make it more readable
lemme just maximize this
and let's test this.
So I click here and you can see
that the content is waiting
0.3 seconds before showing up.
But the problem is, this goes both ways,
both transition in and transition out.
So when I go back, it's
also waiting 0.3 seconds.
As a result, you can see
that both transition in
and out are symmetrical.
So to solve this,
we're gonna use asymmetrical transition.
So right before AnyTransition,
I'm going to do, dot,
and then here we can see asymmetric.
So we're gonna select this,
double click it,
and you can see that it
is expecting AnyTransition
for both insertion and removal.
So let me cut the whole
AnyTransition with these modifiers.
So command + X, and I'm
going to replace insertion.
Let's put insertion in its own line,
as well as removal.
And now we can also paste
for the other AnyTransition.
But for the second one,
which is the removal,
this is where we can remove .delay.
So remove .delay, including
the parentheses as well.
And since we only have a single option,
we don't need the value type anymore.
So now we have opacity
and the animation timing.
That's pretty cool.
So now when I transition in,
you can see that the content is waiting.
When I transition out,
it disappears instantly.
Using this technique,
you're going to be able
to have different animation timings
between transition in and out.
So let me just fix the indentation here
and then remove this extra space.
This is where we can start
having multiple cards
and see what kind of complexity
that we're gonna run into.
First of all, let's create a V stack,
so that we can have a second card.
So clicking on a first course item,
embed that in a V stack.
And then right after
the first course item,
create another course item, parentheses.
Let's use the same size.
So let's copy .frame modifier
and apply that to the second card.
Let's add a bit of spacing.
So parentheses for the
V stack, spacing 220.
So when we click on the card,
it's gonna show the full screen,
but only between the first course item
and the full screen course item.
And that's because they're a match.
So the first course item has an ID card
and this full view course
item has the same ID.
You can imagine that if we
have, let's say 20 cards,
each of those cards will
have to have a unique ID
and that unique ID has to
match the full screen ID.
So that's where having multiple cards
using matched symmetry
can get pretty complex
and it's not matched symmetry's fault.
It's just the way we wanna
set up the animations
and the transitions that
requires a lot of setup.
But don't worry,
we're going to try the
simplest route possible
while keeping all the powerful features.
Before we move to the next session,
let's fix the background color
so that it doesn't seem
overlapping like this.
We're gonna go to the scroll view,
and at the end of it,
before the transition,
we're gonna set .background.
We're gonna use one of our color assets.
So color, parentheses, it's
going to be Background 1.
We set up Background 1 to
be white for light mode
and black for dark mode.
So now when we go to full screen,
you can see that the content is scrollable
and it's not overlapping anymore.
Next, we're gonna make
this main screen of cards
to be scrollable as well.
So let's command click on V stack
and embed in V stack
and replace by a scroll view.
Now the content is scrollable,
but you're gonna notice
that since the scroll view
is clipping the content,
we have to make sure that the
content inside the scroll view
takes the full width.
And to solve that, we're
going to add a modifier
for V stack,
.frame, parentheses
MaxWidth:
.infinity
Awesome.
Now we can see that both of
our screens are scrollable
and transitioning perfectly.
In the next session we're going to play
with an array of cards,
using a data model.
We're going to pass the data to each card
so that the content is unique.
And then we're going to match the cards
using matched symmetry effect.
So I'll see you in the next session.
(outro beat)