(air whooshing)
(upbeat music)
- [Meng] Hi there, welcome
to my SwiftUI course,
section 17, today, we're gonna learn
how to set deeper
navigation inside our app.
So right now, if we tap
on any of these sessions,
it doesn't do anything.
We have a custom transition,
but we would like to have the ability
to navigate to each of these sections
by either using a modal or
the default slide navigation.
So let's scroll down a little
bit to find the content
that is right here.
Right after latest sections,
you're gonna find the LazyVGrid,
and we're going to Command
click on the course row
to embed in VStack and change
VStack to navigation link.
Let's add parentheses and then destination
for which we're going to set
course detail parentheses.
So the course detail requires a namespace.
And in our courses view,
we have the namespace,
which is already attach
to this transition.
So we'll have to create another one
to satisfy this requirement.
So let's type namespace, var namespace2.
Then let's go back to navigation link.
And this is where we're
going to input namespace
to namespace2, great.
If you resume your preview and
you scroll down a little bit,
you're gonna find that
these are great out.
And that's because for the
preview to run navigation link,
it needs the navigation view.
But in this case, it is available
from either the sidebar or the tab bar.
And we didn't include that
here in the courses view
because we didn't want to
repeat the navigation view.
So we'll have to test that
in the device directly.
So when you run the app,
it includes a tab bar,
which has the navigation view,
and therefore the navigation
link will work as well.
So when we tap, it's going
to do this default transition
where you can swipe and go back.
Now the navigation
link, just like a button
is going to try to tint your content.
So you're gonna have to
set a color for the text,
but also if it's an image
which we already did,
set it to rendering mode original.
So back in courses view, let's
command click on course row,
jump to definition,
and then for the title,
we're gonna set dot foreground
color, set it to dot primary.
Now this is the color
already set by default,
if you haven't set anything,
but also if you use the navigation
link, it takes priority,
which means you're gonna have
to set the primary color.
In other words, this is a system color
and in light mode it's black,
in dark mode it's white.
For the secondary color, it
has different tones of gray
for light and dark modes.
Now for the modal presentation,
we're gonna go to course detail.
Let's resume our preview.
Then we'll select the course row.
Then we'll add a new
modifier called dot sheet.
Now in the second option you're gonna find
is presented content.
So is presented is a boolean
and content is the destination.
So let's set the boolean after endif.
Let's type state var show modal
is equal to false by default.
Then going back to the sheet modifier,
we're gonna set is
presented to show modal,
and don't forget the
dollar sign in front of it.
This means that it's a binding.
Now for the content we
can write it this way,
or we can just remove the
comma with the content
and curly braces and put the curly braces
after the parenthesis.
And here we're gonna set the
destination to course list.
Next, we're gonna have to set the action.
Right after dot sheet, we're
gonna set dot on tap gesture.
Again, we can make this cleaner
by deleting the parentheses
and then curly braces.
We're going to set show
modal is equal to true.
Now, if you resume your
preview and click on play,
since the modal doesn't
require a navigation view,
you're gonna be able to test
it right here by tapping
on each of the course row.
And this is the default
behavior, you can scroll,
but also you can swipe
from the top to dismiss it.
Please keep in mind that it
looks a little bit different
on the device.
If you go to the full screen
mode and tap on the course row,
it's gonna show the modal
with a black background underneath.
Another thing to keep note
is that if you're using the modal,
you're gonna have to keep
an eye on the corner radius.
To solve that we can set
the iOS corner radius
to 10 instead of 22, so
this will solve our issue.
Next I wanna show you
how to dismiss the modal
using a close button,
but first we're gonna create a new view.
Let's press command + N to
create a new SwiftUI file,
select SwiftUI view.
We'll name this course section detail,
targeting iOS and macOS.
Let me show the preview.
Then I'm gonna start right
away with a close button.
So close button parentheses.
I'll put this to the top right.
So Command, click on
it, embed it in VStack,
set to ZStack instead,
then parentheses after,
alignment to top trailing.
Now it's not gonna do anything
because the ZStack size
is this much.
So just like VStack, the
alignment applies to the items
in relation to each other.
Now I'm going to add some
content before the close button.
Let's start with the
course item, parentheses.
Now, because the course item
is taking the full screen,
the close button is
aligning against that space.
For the course item, I'm gonna set a frame
with a height of 300.
I'm also going to set a
corner radius to zero.
Then I'll put this course
item inside a Vstack first,
then change that VStack to scroll view.
After that I'm going to
put a bunch of texts.
So let's start with text
Command, click on the text,
embed in Vstack.
For the text, I'm just
gonna copy and paste
from my text content.
You can get this from
the design code page,
and at the end of the VStack,
after the curly braces,
I'm going to add a modifier
or padding parentheses.
And then for the VStack, I'm
going to add parenthesis,
alignment to dot leading
comma, spacing to 30.
Let's scroll down a little bit.
We're gonna find the close button
and let's add a bit of padding.
So padding parentheses.
For closing the modal,
we're gonna have to set
an environment variable.
So right before body, we're
gonna set at environment,
parentheses backwards slash
dot presentation mode,
then var presentation mode.
Going back to the bottom,
right after close button,
we're going to set on tap gesture.
And again, we can clean
this by just keeping
the curly braces and set presentation mode
dot wrapped value dot dismiss.
Great. Now we can go
back to course detail.
And this is where instead
of calling course lists,
we're going to use course section detail.
Now, if you test this on the device,
you're gonna see that we're
gonna go to the modal.
Everything works perfectly,
and the dismiss button
works as well, awesome.
There are just two things
you need to be aware of
for the Mac.
So going back to courses view,
we're gonna find the navigation link.
If you test this on the Mac,
so let me select this and run.
Navigation link is a little
bit buggy on the beta
and it has its own styling.
So instead of using navigation link,
I would definitely use a
transition that we learned earlier
with a preset or a custom one
using matchedGeometryEffect.
For now, we're gonna set a
condition so pound if OS iOS,
then after that else, and endif.
For the Mac, we're simply not
gonna use navigation link.
So just copy and paste course
row. Next issue is the modal.
So when you go to full screen mode
and you tap one of the rows,
the width of the modal is going
to use all available space.
So you're gonna have to
limit the width and height.
Let's go back to course section detail,
scroll to the very top.
We're gonna change body to content.
And before content, we're
going to create var body
of type some view, curly braces,
because body is the first
thing it's going to load.
Inside the curly braces,
we're gonna put content
and also we're gonna set
the platform conditions.
So before content, pound
if OS iOS else, endif.
For the Mac, we're gonna set
content with a frame modifier,
parentheses with 800, height 600.
Awesome, so now we can go to the modal
and it's going to be 800 by 600.
In the next session,
I wanna show you how to set
the nav bar and the tab bar
to be underneath this
full screen animation.
As a result, we won't have to
set a custom large title here,
and we can use that nav bar.
Likewise for the iPhone,
the content is going to
be above the tab bar,
which is a lot nicer.
So I'll see you in the next session.
(upbeat music)