(upbeat music)
- [Meng] Hey there,
welcome to our third session
of the SwiftUI course.
Today we're gonna to learn
how to use SF symbols
to create these lists layouts
that you can see everywhere in iOS.
In the content of each session,
I'm trying to link to resources
that are being discussed,
such as the SF Symbols app,
which you should download
for SF Symbols 2.
And also,
there are a bunch of Dub Dub DC videos
that you can find the
developer app by Apple.
And here, you can search
for SF symbols for example,
and there, you have SF
symbol two, as a video.
Again, these resources will be
linked from the text content.
Now focusing on the new SF symbols
now we have access to multicolor symbols,
but also I'm going to show you
how to use them in SwiftUI,
and how to create a list styles.
So back in Xcode,
we're going to create a new file,
and we're going to do Command N.
This is going to create
a new SwiftUI view.
So we're gonna select this one next.
We're gonna name that CourseRow.
You can use the naming convention row
for any repeatable element in the list.
First things first, we're
gonna resume the preview,
and then we're going to replace text
by image, parentheses, system name.
So at this point, we're
just gonna go fully code,
because it's easier to debug,
it's easier to control,
and as you get used to
it, it's just faster.
Now while you do that,
make sure that you're always
using the auto-completion,
because names and values
can be rather long,
but also programming is not forgiving,
in terms of caps, lowercase and symbols.
So back to our code,
here it is expecting a name.
And in this case,
we can use the SF symbol name.
If you go to SF symbols,
we're going to go to Multicolor.
And let's select this
one called paperplane.
There's a shortcut to copy the code.
So in Edit, it's Copy Name,
and the shortcut is Shift Command and C.
So Shift Command C.
Back to Xcode,
we're going to paste that
inside double quotes,
like this.
Now you're gonna to see the icon.
It's barely visible because
it's very small by default.
But if you zoom in, you
can see it more clearly.
You can also make it bigger,
so it has three sizes.
And we can use a modifier.
So, right after image,
we're going to type dot imageScale.
And then you can have medium
and if you press dot you're gonna find
all the options available
to us in this context.
So, you can also have large.
So if you want to use
the multicolor option,
we have to add a modifier
before the imageScale,
so, dot renderingMode,
then, dot original.
So with this technique,
you have access to all 2400 icons
without importing any asset related to it.
And on top of that,
it works for the Mac as well,
and you can change the font size
to perfectly match the text
and even match the font weight,
which is equivalent to the
stroke width of the icon.
Now, I do want to point out
that if you're using the font properties,
you're not going to be
able to use the multicolor,
so the renderingMode and the imageScale
will not be very useful,
because the font size
changes the size of the icon.
But first of all, let me
add a text next to the icon.
So let me insert,
it's going To take care
of the stack for me.
And I'm going to insert a text.
Selecting the text,
drag and drop to the right of the icon.
So I can change the font size individually
for the text and image,
but I can also put the
modifier in the container
and it's going to apply
to both at the same time.
Let me do that.
So right after HStack,
I'm going to type dot font, Enter,
and then set it to title.
So what you're noticing here,
is that the font is being applied
to both of these elements.
But also, the renderingMode
no longer works.
And if I change the font
size to large title,
both the icon and the text will resize.
Now if you want to change the font weight,
as well as the stroke width of the icon,
we'll have to replace
large title by system.
And here we have a bunch of options,
such as size, weight and design.
So we're going to select this one.
And now we can set a
custom font size such as,
let's say 34, which is the
size of the large title.
And the font weight
can be, let's say bold.
And for the font, if you type dot,
you're going to find that you have
the choice between
default which is SF Pro,
mono spaces, SF mono,
SF routed for rounded
and series is New York.
Let's use rounded.
Now you're gonna see that
the text is more rounded,
but the icon is not changed by the font.
It's only changed by the
weight, as well as the size.
So if I set it to, let's say light,
you're gonna see that the icon is lighter.
And likewise for the text.
Now, remember about the imageScale,
I can use medium now or small
depending on the ratio that
I want versus the text.
Okay, so this layout here
is fairly common for,
let's say a menu.
But what if I want a second line of text.
So let's just add a new text,
and drag that right
underneath the first text.
So it's going to create a
VStack containing both text.
So now I'm just going to
change back my dot system
to dot subheadline.
Now make sure that there's
only one set of parentheses.
And instead of applying
both the icon and the text,
I'm just going to cut it so Command X,
and just put it on the first title.
Then I'm going to paste the same modifier
on the second title.
For the second title,
I'm gonna set it to dot footnote.
Let's change the text.
So the first one SwiftUI,
the second one, we're
going to change it to,
let's say Description.
I'm going to add a bold to the first text,
so dot bold parentheses.
Next, I'll make sure
that within my VStack,
I'm going to align the text to the left.
So, in the inspector, click
on alignment to the left.
Speaking of inspector versus code,
we're going to select the second text.
And here in color,
you're gonna see that I don't have access
to some of the system color.
And one of them is called secondary,
which is really useful because
it adapts across devices.
Let's go to after dot font,
we're going to type dot foregroundColor,
and instead of blue, we're
going to set dot secondary.
This color should not be confused
with the ones in the assets catalog.
And this is really useful
because it adapts to dark mode.
All right, so let me select the VStack.
Let's set a spacing of four.
And then for the HStack,
I'm going to set the
alignment to top. Great.
Now I'm going to make my
frame of my icon bigger.
So, selecting image,
I'm going to go to frame
and set it to 48 by 48.
Then I'm going to add a
modifier called background,
then add another one called clip shape,
which allows me to mask
around any shape that I want.
In this case, by default,
it's set to a circle.
Since both my background
and my image is blue,
I should probably add another
one called foregroundColor
to change the color of the icon,
I'm going to set it to white.
This is not applying
because the renderingMode
is set to original,
I might want to use template instead.
This allows me to color
the icon as I wish.
And so in this case, it's set to white.
Okay, so we can add a spacer to the right
in order to push everything
to take the full width.
Let's go to right after VStack
and type Spacer parentheses.
Awesome. Now that I have my
row, I can create a new screen.
So let's do that.
Command N, select SwiftUI View.
Name it CoursesView.
Let's resume this.
And then I can replace my text
with CourseRow parentheses.
And now, you can see that I'm referencing
the UI element that I
just created earlier.
And to create my list layout,
I can just Command click on CourseRow
to get to a contextual menu,
and I can select embed in list.
Boom! Now I have my list UI,
and I can repeat as many times as I want,
such as 20,
and it's going to be scrollable.
If you want to be able to
interact with the preview,
you need to click on play.
And this is where you can
scroll the content like this.
Now talking about list styles,
we're gonna go to list
and add a modifier called
dot List Style.
And here you don't really know
what list styles are available to you,
not even the inspector is helpful.
So one thing you can do,
which is super useful,
is to Option Click on any modifier
to get to the documentation.
And you can click on ListStyle.
This will open the built-in documentation,
and then you can scroll,
and here you have a bunch
of types that you can use.
For example, we can use
InsetGroupedListStyle,
and then paste that right
here, at parentheses.
So just like that,
I'm able to have a beautiful new UI
based on my custom design,
which is the CourseRow,
and the icon that can be
changed to any of the 2400s.
That's really powerful.
So I hope you enjoyed this session.
In the next one,
we're gonna to explore
how to create a sidebar
and how to implement the new label.
So I'll see you in the next session.