(theater sounds)
(upbeat music)
[Instructor] Hello, welcome to session 11
of my SwiftUI course.
In this session,
we're going to learn how
to apply the transition
to every single card separately.
Before we start, I just wanna
organize my data model here.
Previously, we created
Course.swift for our data.
So we're gonna right click on that file,
and then New Group from Selection.
We're going to name this one Model.
I'm just gonna drag it
right after Navigation,
but make sure you're not
inside the Navigation.
After that, let's get back to CoursesView.
So, what we wanna do
here for the full screen
is instead of using the Boolean show,
we're just gonna check if
there's a selected item.
In order to do that, we're gonna
have to create a new state.
So, state var selected item,
which is of type course.
And by default, we wanna
set it to empty, so nil,
like this, if there is no item selected,
it's just not going to
show the full screen.
Now, Swift has something called optional,
and optional means that if it's possible
that there's no value,
then the data needs a question
mark to mean optional.
So thanks for that,
we're gonna be able to go
to the if show statement,
which is now using a Boolean.
And instead, we're gonna ask
if the selected item is not
nil, which means it's not empty.
So, we know that by default,
it's going to be empty,
which means that it's not
gonna show any full screen.
Right now it's not gonna do anything
because when we tap on a card,
it's only toggling the show state.
If we go to the tab
gesture at the very end,
you can see that we're
toggling the show state.
Now, in addition to doing that,
we should also change the selected item
to the one being tapped.
But right now because we
are not inside the loop,
we don't know which one is being tapped.
So, what we need to do here
is to get the onTapGesture modifier.
So, all of this modifier, cut,
and then put that to
the first course item,
right after frame.
Because of this, every single card
is going to have a tab gesture.
So now right after
show.toggle parentheses,
we're going to set selected
item is equal to item.
Item, meaning the specific data
that we're getting from the courses array.
Now for the selected item,
we're going to replace the
one being entered manually
by the value that we're getting
from the selected item.
So, selected item,
and here we're getting an error
because the value that we need to pass
to the component cannot be empty.
So, we need to add an exclamation point
to mean that we know for
sure that selected item
is not gonna be empty, otherwise,
it wouldn't have passed this
condition in the first place.
And then we need to do the same
for the match symmetry effect ID.
So selected item, exclamation point.
And that's it.
Now, we can tap on any of these cards
to go to full screen mode.
But now since we have only the tap gesture
for going to full screen,
we also need the tap
gesture for going back.
Otherwise, we won't be able
to tap back to the cards.
So, let's select this whole
modifier onTopGesture,
and then we're going to
Command + C to copy it.
Then we're gonna go to
the second course item,
right after to frame
and then paste that onTapGesture.
For the selected item, we
need to put it back to nil.
So, let's test our UI.
And here you can see
that it's working great.
The only issue with the
selected item technique
is that if you switch
between cards too fast,
it's not gonna animate well.
And that's because the selected item
is changing before the animation is over.
So, while this selected item
technique is very clean,
we also need to make sure that
during the transition out,
we're not gonna be able
to select right away
to the next item before
we finish the animation.
For the transition in,
it's fine because it's still
focusing on a single card.
So, let's take care of the transition out.
So, we're gonna create a
new state at the top state.
State var, this is going to
be a Boolean, so isDisabled
is equal to false by default.
So, what we're going to do
is to disable the cards
while the transition out
animation is happening.
So let's click resume
after setting the state.
And then during the onTapGesture,
we're going to set isDisable to true,
meaning that we will be
able to disable the cards.
So, using this state,
we can add a new modifier
for the course item,
right after onTapGesture to disabled,
and this is a Boolean,
which means that we can use our state,
so isDisabled. Great.
So what should happen is
that when we tap on a card,
it's going to do the animation,
and then we cannot have any more
because at this point,
everything has been disabled.
We just need to enable them
back at the right timing.
So, let's scroll down and
find the auto onTapGesture.
Here after selected item,
we're gonna set isDisable
is equal to false.
But you're gonna notice that
it's going to happen too fast,
and it's not going to solve our issue.
Now, what we can do is to add a delay.
So, let's set
dispatchQueue.main.asyncAfter.
And now we're going to set the timing,
which is dot now which
means now plus 0.3 second.
So, this code is a little bit complicated,
but it just means that
we're gonna wait 0.3 seconds
before running the code.
So, let's go to the next
value and press Enter.
And this is where we can put
isDisabled is equal to false.
So, let me cut that and
paste that right here.
Now, what should happen
is that when I tap here,
the cards are disabled.
And when I tap back to the cards,
it's still going to be disabled,
but only for 0.3 second,
and again, this depends on
the timing of your animation.
For me, after a lot of
testing and clicking,
I noticed that 0.5 works best.
So, now we cannot break the UI anymore.
Alright, so that's what I
wanted to show you today.
In the next session,
we're going to look
into the new Lazy Grid.
We're gonna make our
layouts so much cooler,
and so much more adaptive
while still using the same transitions.
So I'm pretty excited
to show you Lazy Grid in the next session.
See you then.