(upbeat music)
- [Meng] Hey there,
welcome to my SwiftUI
course session seven.
Today we're gonna start
a long series of videos
around matched geometry.
Along the way, we're gonna
learn a bunch of new techniques
such as asymmetric
transition, selection state,
lazyGrid, etcetera.
First of all, let's start
by switching to iOS.
I'm gonna select iPhone 11 for preview,
so click on resume.
Instead of the text here,
we're gonna put CourseItem parentheses.
So this is the cart design
that we have created earlier.
And now we're gonna set a fixed frame,
so dot frame with a width
of 335 and a height of 250.
Now what we want to do is
when we tap on this cart
is gonna show up full screen view.
In order to do that,
we're gonna have to place
this CourseItem inside
a VStack first and change
from VStack to ZStack.
This will allow us to have
many carts on top of each other
three dimensionally,
instead of stacking
vertically or horizontally.
Now we're gonna set the new view
CourseItem parentheses,
then we're gonna make
sure that this new view
is not shown by default.
So we're gonna have to set a state.
State var show is equal to false.
Then we're gonna add a condition
for the second course item.
Let's wrap it inside a VStack first,
and change from VStack to if show.
Whenever you update your variables,
you're gonna have to resume the preview.
And when you do that,
then the full screen will
be not shown by defaults.
Let's add a tap gesture,
so that when we tap on this cart,
it's gonna show the full screen.
Let's place that for the
ZStack, so everything.
So after ZStack dot TapGesture,
and this is where we're gonna type
show dot toggle parentheses.
This will ensure that every
time that we tap on the cart,
it's gonna switch between true and false.
Let's click on play.
And now when we tap the
cart, it switch to full mode.
And again, back and forth.
Of course, we're gonna need to transition,
so we can set dot animation,
and by default is gonna set to easeIn,
which creates a simple
fade in fade out animation.
If you want to customize this transition,
you're going to need to place a modifier
on the first parent
container inside the if show.
So let's put dot transition.
And here, if you type dot,
you have a bunch of options,
such as opacity, which is by default.
But otherwise, you also have slide.
And here, it's gonna slide from the left,
and then move to the right.
Now, what you're noticing here,
is that when you do the transition out,
then suddenly the cart
goes behind the first cart,
and that's not what we want.
Normally, you would solve
this using a zIndex,
such as dot zIndex.
Insert a value of one.
But during this beta,
it seems to be a little bit buggy,
especially when you click multiple times.
And don't worry, we're gonna
explore zIndex more later.
But a quick solution that I found.
So I'm gonna remove the
zIndex, so now its smooth.
Is to put the if show inside a VStack.
So let's put the Vstack, curly braces,
and I'm gonna cut everything
for the if statement
and paste it inside the VStack.
If you do this,
then your new view is
gonna always be on top.
And now we can explore the
other transitions such as scale.
And this is what it looks like.
Then a very useful one
is to use move using one of the edges.
A common transition is from trailing,
which means from the right,
and so, it's a screen
that goes from the right
and then that hides back.
If you want your full
screen to not be restricted
by the safe area,
then you can add a modifier
dot edgeIgnoringSafeArea dot all.
So now you're going to see
a beautiful full screen mode
that slide from the right.
And we can change from which
direction it comes from.
Bottom is also very common, like this,
almost like a modal but
without the stacking carts
as well as the gesture.
At the same time, unlike the modal,
these trends additions
are very customizable.
I can also put it from leading,
which is from the left.
And then in terms of animation,
we can change to easeIn out.
So that means that it's gonna be slow
at the beginning of the
animation and at the end.
And a lot more options such
as duration, delay, repeat,
which I explore quite a
lot in my previous course.
For now, let's focus on
spring, which is really neat,
because it's going to bounce a little bit.
It gives us that effect
that you see a lot on iOS.
But I do want to point out that
while this is a good way
to set up the animation,
you can also do it during the action.
So here I'm gonna type
withAnimation curly braces,
and I'm gonna bring show
dot toggle inside it.
Let's disable dot animation modifier
and just focus on withAnimation.
Now I just wanna point
out that in the preview,
it's going to appear instantly,
and then disappear correctly.
But that's not the case
when you run the app.
In iOS simulator,
you're gonna see that
the animation is correct.
So the reason why I'm exploring both here
is to give you options,
but also because this is
the correct way to do it
when you're using matched geometry effect.
Let me resume this.
Then again,
you can see that when I click
first it instantly appear,
but when I click multiple
times, it runs fine.
So that's just to keep in mind
with withAnimation correctly.
If you want to add the animation timing
is gonna be parenthesis,
after withAnimation,
so dot spring parentheses.
Another thing to note is that
when you use withAnimation,
the timing might be a
little bit different.
So the speed of the animation
versus using dot animation modifier.
So with this,
you should have a to
create a preset animation
between screens,
and this is gonna work across platform
including the Mac and iPad.
In the next session,
we're gonna use matched geometry effect.
And we're gonna be able
to compare the difference
between having a preset transition
versus transitioning shared elements
using matched geometry effect.
So I'll see you in the next session.